<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book Review on DevOps Confusion</title>
    <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book Review on DevOps Confusion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015, Nick Klauer; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 01:33:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Into Thin Air by Jon Krakauer</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/book-review-into-thin-air-by-jon-krakauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 01:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/book-review-into-thin-air-by-jon-krakauer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A story about the tragic events of the 1996 Mount Everest disaster, this story as told by Jon Krakauer&amp;ndash;one of only two members to survive on his team&amp;ndash;tells in vivid detail the confusion surrounding what happened up on Mount Everest May 10-11 1996.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was a good, entertaining read about a horribly tragic story.  The 1996 Mount Everest Disaster is known to be the highest death toll in one day.  The reasons for this are many, but the author speculates that it was summed up by a few details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Too many people summitting at the same time causing blocks and slow passage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An unexpected weather event struck the mountain that was not expected or forecast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two teams that tried to summit&amp;ndash;one by veteran climber Rob Hall, another by rising climber Scott Fischer&amp;ndash;were possibly competing with each other for notoriety, and subsequently ignored their usual turn around time of 2PM by a wide wide margin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Into-Thin-Air-ebook/dp/B000FC1ITK/ref=sr_1_5?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1327866663&amp;amp;sr=8-5&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/516WCfinpvL._BO2,204,203,200_PIsitb-sticker-arrow-click,TopRight,35,-76_AA300_SH20_AA278_PIkin4,BottomRight,-49,22_AA300_SH20_OU01_.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Into Thin Air : Kindle Edition&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was a good story, and I finished it in a couple days.  It was sad what happened to the people on that summit, but as I was reading it I was struck by a confusion around why people with so little experience or skill in mountain climbing, would ever attempt such a dangerous trek.  To pay $60-70K on one trip up to the summit seems high, but it also seems frustratingly stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the military, we&amp;rsquo;ve taken to training in extreme conditions on occassion.  These are labeled &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; because it exposed us to conditions were weren&amp;rsquo;t usually prepared for or skilled in, and allowed us to test our limits in the confines of a safe territory, rather than on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In none of my &amp;lsquo;training adventures&amp;rsquo; did I think it worth paying for, nor would I do it simply because I could.  I did it because I was part of a team, training for the military with the assumption that these skills would be used for war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why anyone in this book wanted to do it, and I may never understand.  Tragically, both the leaders of the expedition&amp;ndash;Rob Hall and Scott Fischer&amp;ndash;were fathers or soon-to-be fathers with wives of their own at home.  Their children never saw them again, and Rob never had a chance to raise his firstborn child, as his wife was 7 months pregnant at the time of his death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly all of the other people who died had families and lives outside of this trip, which has doubtfully put undue stress on their families to adjust and attempt to move on.  I don&amp;rsquo; t know how I would handle it, but I doubt I could ever forgive myself for letting my spouse travel to a place for no other reason than their own personal pursuit of &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Rating : 3.5 / 5 stars or so.  It&amp;rsquo;s a good read, albeit a tragic one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Slack by Tom DeMarco</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/book-review-slack-by-tom-demarco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 06:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/book-review-slack-by-tom-demarco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/123715.Slack&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://photo.goodreads.com/books/1320419657m/123715.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Slack: Getting Past Burnout, Busywork, and the Myth of Total Efficiency&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/123715.Slack&#34;&gt;Slack: Getting Past Burnout, Busywork, and the Myth of Total Efficiency&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38238.Tom_DeMarco&#34;&gt;Tom DeMarco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/review/show/256690418&#34;&gt;3 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure this is full of really useful information for people unfamiliar with it, but after having read Drive by Dan Pink, as well as having witnessed leadership in the military and warzones, this kind of fell flat for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the advice and information felt like common sense to me, so maybe it&amp;rsquo;s valuable to another demographic, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. If there are people that look at this and think their entire management style has been wrong, I sure hope they figure it out soon, because I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to work with you nor would I tolerate your behavior if I was your superior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/review/list/2600826-nick-klauer&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>