<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on DevOps Confusion</title>
    <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on DevOps Confusion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2015, Nick Klauer; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 14:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nickklauer.info/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stack Ranking is Absurd...unless you happen to be weeding officers out of the military</title>
      <link>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/why-stacked-ranking-is-absurd-in-the-workplace-but-might-be-okay-for-indoctrination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nickklauer.info/post/2012/why-stacked-ranking-is-absurd-in-the-workplace-but-might-be-okay-for-indoctrination/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So I found this really interesting article about &lt;a href=&#34;http://stevegall.wetpaint.com/page/Human+Resource+Management&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stacked Ranking&amp;rdquo; employees at Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; from one of Zed Shaw&amp;rsquo;s tweets, and it reminded me of something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/klauern/status/220704644861657088&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/klauern/status/220704644861657088&lt;/a&gt; align=&amp;lsquo;center&amp;rsquo;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can tell you a thing or two about how I participated in this minor experiment while in the military.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stacked-ranking-at-ocs:c6074c9ccb4db6afe563e0233086de4b&#34;&gt;Stacked Ranking at OCS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with stacked ranking comes from a time long ago when I was attending an officer candidate school for the Marine Corps.  I was probably 21 at the time, and had just recently finished boot camp to become an enlisted Marine in the Reserves.  This was all part of my plan, of course, to get the enlisted experience under my belt before stepping in to the officer world.  I thought, &amp;ldquo;I want to be an officer in the Marine Corps, I should try to do something to gain some respect first&amp;rdquo;, and joined the Marines enlisted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, with my almost inconsequential level of experience in the military (probably less than 9 months) I attended one of the most difficult courses that I have ever heard about, witnessed, or will ever likely face again: &lt;a href=&#34;http://officer.marines.com/marine/making_marine_officers/officer_candidates_school&#34;&gt;Officer Candidate School&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course can vary in length, depending on the route you take to get there.  People in college in the ROTC program attend a 8- or 10-week course, while other types of groups face a 10- or 2 separate 6-week courses.  I was in the latter camp.  This program is called PLC or &lt;a href=&#34;http://officer.marines.com/marine/making_marine_officers/commissioning_programs/platoon_leaders_class&#34;&gt;Platoon Leaders Class&lt;/a&gt;.  It is spread out over two summers, whereby you go through hell the first summer 6-week program to partially graduate so you can attend the second 6-week course that&amp;rsquo;s harder than the first.  It&amp;rsquo;s not easy. It puts a toll on your physical ability, endurance, decision making skills, and is generally a way to weed out people that won&amp;rsquo;t make decisions in stressful situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the first of the two courses, where you really find that there are people of all walks of life wanting to be an officer in the Marine Corps.  The requirement for Officers is a 4-year bachelor degree, a set minimum GPA (varies depending on the need), and to be able to pass a physical fitness test by some score.  There is no mental test, SAT score, acceptance criteria, etc., besides this, so you will often find that someone from some random university (such as mine: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uwplatt.edu/&#34;&gt;University of Wisconsin-Platteville&lt;/a&gt;) working side-by-side with people in completely other classes of ivy league (Rutgers, Harvard, USC, Yale, Notre Dame, Big-10 schools, etc.).  Most of these people aren&amp;rsquo;t here because they were curious: leadership is what they were sold on, and they&amp;rsquo;re here to prove to themselves they can do it.  You immediately find yourself among people generally more physically fit, competent, and capable than most people you have ever seen before.  If you felt like a big fish in a small pond, you find yourself to be very humbled to be working next to these people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this course is 6-weeks, meaning that you generally get about 5 hours of sleep a night for 6 straight weeks.  There are some minor allowances given to you after three weeks in, but by that point, you&amp;rsquo;re so used to the rhythm or lack of sleep you&amp;rsquo;ll just use those 12 hour freedom periods as catchup for sleep.  Most of this course is meant more to test you and validate that you&amp;rsquo;re capable of being an officer.  In the enlisted side, you sign a contract for 4 or 6 years before you even go to bootcamp, so the expectation from the get-go is that &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ve got your ass for X years, we&amp;rsquo;ll drag you across the finish line to get there&amp;rdquo;.  Your commitment was decided on paper, and the government will hold you to that.  That&amp;rsquo;s not the case at all with officer candidate school.  Officers are the ones held ultimately responsible for all actions in batte, war, logistics, and running the show.  They decide what happens, while the enlisted side makes sure it does happen.  Because of this, most contracts aren&amp;rsquo;t signed until after verifying you&amp;rsquo;re competent, which means passing OCS.  There&amp;rsquo;s a reason it&amp;rsquo;s called a &amp;ldquo;candidate&amp;rdquo; school, and it&amp;rsquo;s more a test to weed you out from the less likely and less useful peers.  Doing this is one day is not uncommon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;wake up at 5AM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;get dressed for PT by 5:10&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;stretching for PT by 5:30&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;running 4, 5 miles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;some team building exercise, with an emphasis on this being exercise&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;cool down&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;breakfast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;done by 7&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;dressed for the day of training&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;some classes in the morning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;run to lunch&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;run back to classes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;more tests, questions berating of your ability, knowledge, and decision-making skills throughout the day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;evening chow&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;clean up&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;test, study, prep for next day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;lights out at 10PM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;wake up for fire watch for an hour at 1AM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;do laundry&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;finish fire watch at 2AM&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;go to bed at 2:15&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;wake up at 5 again&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit off-topic at this point, but let it be known that OCS is not an easy course, and the entire time, you&amp;rsquo;re being tested, vetted, and observed like a lab rat to see if you&amp;rsquo;ll get to the piece of cheese in the requisite amount of time or not.  as part of these ongoing classes, tests, etc., the instructors of the course are always critiquing you, testing your ability to retain knowledge quickly and recite, repeat, and train others in the same, and evaluated frequently on your small-unit and large-unit leadership skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big tests that happens at the end is the &amp;ldquo;Peer Review&amp;rdquo; session, whereby each candidate in your area is handed a sheet numbered 1-100.  You rank the names of everybody besides you on them, offering a comment or two if you think they deserve something.  The guy you think is the best, put him at #1.  The worst? #100 (or whatever the size of your platoon or class).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this is over, you hand this in, totals are gathered, and you&amp;rsquo;re brought in individually to see your instructors about your score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with a group of people that are often heads and shoulders above your peers in any other place, you find really quickly where you fit in the grand scheme of things.  A lower third rank in this group is devastating, mostly because you know that the people that graded you are also your friends and worked with you these 4 or 5 long weeks together day-in, day-out.  It&amp;rsquo;s much, &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; harder to receive a low or middling score from your peers than it is to receive it from your &amp;lsquo;boss&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-this-relate-to-microsoft-s-stack-rank-method:c6074c9ccb4db6afe563e0233086de4b&#34;&gt;How does this relate to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Stack Rank method?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I see that differs from the stack rank method that is being described in that HR document attached above and what I did here, is the visibility and transparency of it all.  In Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s version, the game is similar, but it&amp;rsquo;s held in groups of managers above you behind closed doors.  The only number you see at the end of the process is something vary blank like &amp;ldquo;3.0&amp;rdquo; meaning &amp;ldquo;middle quartile&amp;rdquo; or whatnot, instead of &amp;ldquo;ranked #30 out of #70 by your peers&amp;rdquo;.  I cannot fathom how management can pretend it&amp;rsquo;s even close to being fair when you take out the peer part of it, leaving the decision making to team managers that likely have no experience of anybody other than their own team and their ability (or lack of ability) to argue and barter their team member&amp;rsquo;s places among the heap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found out about my experience was probably more insightful for my own sake than anything else could have been.  It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to be told by your instructors that you&amp;rsquo;re so-so when they&amp;rsquo;re grading you: they have a limited field of view of your accomplishments and capabilities.  You can easily write their negative appraisals off as being close-minded, lacking any real experience, or just plain bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re reviewed by your peers, it&amp;rsquo;s all laid bare.  These are the people that you spent every waking minute with for the past 6 weeks.  Their opinion is about as good as you can hope to get.  If they dont think you&amp;rsquo;re awesome, it&amp;rsquo;s likely because either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a. you&amp;rsquo;re not, or&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;b. you failed to show them what you really were capable of&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this gives you an incredibly strong feeling about your own ability.  You can think you&amp;rsquo;re the best thing ever, but if a peer-review of your 70 closest teammates can&amp;rsquo;t make that same judgement, there&amp;rsquo;s little doubt the problem with that lies in you and you alone.  Blaming them all for &amp;ldquo;not getting me&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;missing what I can do&amp;rdquo; is completely missing the point.  They all saw you.  They all knew what you were doing, trying to do, or failed to do.  There just weren&amp;rsquo;t enough people who thought you were hot shit to outweigh the rest that thought otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the phrases that I often attribute to great leadership is &amp;ldquo;command presence&amp;rdquo; as it was shown to me time and again at this place.  When someone with &amp;ldquo;command presence&amp;rdquo; walks in to a room, they are given attention and deference.  There are ways to learn this, probably, but many of the best leaders were also ones that could get a group of people to listen to them without raising their voice or pulling their rank around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-stack-ranking-worth-it:c6074c9ccb4db6afe563e0233086de4b&#34;&gt;Is stack ranking worth it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the environment I was in, this method of peer review was both devastating and incredibly useful.  I knew where I stood among my peers, and the only way I could get higher in that rank would be to prove to them that I was better.  I did improve quite a bit over the course of that 6 weeks, and I thank that peer review to a good amount of it&amp;ndash;both there and in life afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I can&amp;rsquo;t see it working well without a huge amount of transparency and trust.  Above all else, even if you were ranked #70 out of #70 in a platoon on that peer review, you were still &amp;lsquo;one of us&amp;rsquo; or part of our team.  There were almost no people that we didn&amp;rsquo;t trust or wouldn&amp;rsquo;t protect in a time of need.  That made these peer reviews a hell of a lot easier to stomach.  I knew the guys at the bottom (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t one at the bottom, but let&amp;rsquo;s say I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the top third, either) and they were down on themselves for a bit, it&amp;rsquo;s true.  But they did do some soul searching after that.   Some of them never returned for the second year, others did and blew it out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made it different from the corporate watered-down version were a couple things.  1.  This was a candidate school, not an ongoing workplace evaluation.  This never took place more than during that time in candidate school.  The people with the lowest ranks were seldom let go, although they were certainly close to it.  2. peer ranking in this environment means the difference between life or death.  Honestly, when you&amp;rsquo;re picking your officer leaders, you have to realize that many of these guys are going to be troop leaders in the field.  These guys are making calls to send a guy out there to clear a room, interview a detainee, or inspect something funny by that bush.  The decisions that officers make lead to real life and death effects.  The last thing you want is to say everybody you went to OCS with was awesome and realize that if you didn&amp;rsquo;t rankthat guy at the bottom, he probably would be out there making bad choices or cowering in fear when the situation got rough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>